<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>learning on 2KAbhishek Blogs</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/tags/learning/</link><description>Recent content in learning on 2KAbhishek Blogs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>©2023 2KAbhishek</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:10:46 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/tags/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Think Like an Architect 🧠🏛️</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/2023/08/how-to-think-like-an-architect-%EF%B8%8F/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:10:46 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/2023/08/how-to-think-like-an-architect-%EF%B8%8F/</guid><description>Have you ever wondered what skills it takes to be a software architect?
While civil architects design awe-inspiring structures that stand the test of time, software architects craft intricate architectures that form the foundation of modern technology. Software architects mold the digital landscape as we know it.
Architects possess a unique mindset that enables them to design and develop robust software architectures. Their ability to think strategically, make informed decisions, and balance trade-offs is vital for creating successful systems.</description></item><item><title>Navigating JavaScript 🤷‍♂️🧭</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/2019/08/navigating-javascript-%EF%B8%8F/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 09:31:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/2019/08/navigating-javascript-%EF%B8%8F/</guid><description>JavaScript is taking the world by storm, once used to add functionality to the web, now it is being used in almost all types of software development.
For example, Using JavaScript you can do things like build Progressive Web Apps (web apps with native app like features) , create desktop apps using electron, make Android &amp;amp; iOS apps with React Native, do server stuff using Node and Express and many more.</description></item><item><title>Hidden World Of Podcasts 🎙️🎧</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/2019/04/hidden-world-of-podcasts-%EF%B8%8F/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:58:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/2019/04/hidden-world-of-podcasts-%EF%B8%8F/</guid><description>What do you have playing on your earphones while traveling, driving or doing something less mentally taxing? I&amp;rsquo;m sure most of your answers will be music and I do love my music.
But there&amp;rsquo;s another form of audio only media out there that can take your ears on a joyride - &amp;quot; Podcasts&amp;quot;
Yes, podcasts a very powerful form of media which is often under explored. Some of you might have never listened to one and that&amp;rsquo;s relatable since I myself discovered podcasts a short time ago.</description></item></channel></rss>