<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>opensource on 2KAbhishek Blogs</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/tags/opensource/</link><description>Recent content in opensource on 2KAbhishek Blogs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>©2022 2KAbhishek</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:10:46 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/tags/opensource/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Five Git Tricks To Make Dev Work Easier ⛑️🤹🏼</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/articles/five-git-tricks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:10:46 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/articles/five-git-tricks/</guid><description>Git is the most widely used version control system in the world, and it is something that every Software Craftsperson should master.
In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll be going through five git tricks that will make your software crafting easier.
Here are the tricks we&amp;rsquo;ll be covering in this article:
Quickly set up Git SSH credentials with GitHub CLI Create a new branch and track it with remote Quickly test changes across branches with the help of stash Split one large branch into multiple Delete a branch from remote Quickly set up Git SSH credentials with GitHub CLI The first thing you want to do before trying out these tricks is to set up git and its credentials.</description></item><item><title>What I Learned From Hacktoberfest 🥳🧑‍💻</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/articles/learnings-from-hacktoberfest/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:01:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/articles/learnings-from-hacktoberfest/</guid><description>I recently completed my Hacktoberfest PRs and This post is for all the people who are struggling to get those Pull Requests in and have to resort to special repositories which are targeted toway Hacktoberfest only (nothing wrong with using these).
But there&amp;rsquo;s another way with which you can make valuable contributions easily to the biggest of projects and later on, look at them and feel proud. 😄
Documentation Matters The secret I&amp;rsquo;m talking about is of documentation, most if not all repositories on GitHub use simple markdown files for their documentation, which are very easy to edit and append to.</description></item><item><title>My Intro To Github Actions ⚙️🤷</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/articles/intro-to-github-actions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/articles/intro-to-github-actions/</guid><description>GitHub actions are something that I was always curious about but never really explored, thanks to this hackathon I took a dive and was able to come up with something that actually solves one of my problems.
Gulp Runner Like many of us, I have a personal site deployed on GitHub Pages. 🌐
It uses SCSS so I have to convert it to CSS pre-deployment, I also like to have my scripts and styles minified.</description></item><item><title>Manage GitHub Projects Easily ♻📂</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/articles/manage-your-github-projects/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/articles/manage-your-github-projects/</guid><description>Do you have a lot of repositories on GitHub and are always making changes to them? Do you work on multiple machines, and are struggling to keep the repositories in sync? Have you ever moved to a new machine and spent what seems like an eternity cloning all your projects one by one?
If your answer to any of these questions was yes, well I have a solution for you.</description></item><item><title>Sync Forked Repository With Upstream 🔁✔️</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/articles/sync-forked-repository/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 13:24:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/articles/sync-forked-repository/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the situation, You have forked a repository on GitHub, you have made your changes and sent a pull request, and that request has been merged.
Now you want to make further changes, but the repository mentions that you are X commits ahead or/and X commits behind upstream repository.
So how do you sync it?
You can delete your fork and fork the original repository again, but that is a very tedious thing to do.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Actually Loves️ Linux? 🐧❤</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/articles/microsoft-loves-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 08:40:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/articles/microsoft-loves-linux/</guid><description>Any of you who use npm should have received a mail and that is the reason behind this post.
Microsoft has made a lot of progress in between Steve Ballmer&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Linux is a cancer&amp;rdquo; and Satya Nadella&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Microsoft ♥ Linux&amp;rdquo; in the Open Source world. Most of what microsoft has been doing recently is very inclusive of OSS.
Things from the top of my head include WSL, VS Code, GitHub, Dot Net Core, Powershell and now npm and the list is very long.</description></item></channel></rss>