<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>webdev on 2KAbhishek Blogs</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/tags/webdev/</link><description>Recent content in webdev on 2KAbhishek Blogs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>©2022 2KAbhishek</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 10:36:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/tags/webdev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Links - Present Your Links In Style 🔗🔮</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/articles/links-showcase/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 10:36:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/articles/links-showcase/</guid><description>Have you ever wanted a place that can make all your profiles and links nicely organized, easily searchable and with super customizability?
Well, now you can!
Introducing links Present all your links in style with an easily accessible and highly customizable web app! ✨
Inspiration Needed a place to display all my profiles, used my project&amp;rsquo;s repo as inspiration.
Getting links To get links, follow these steps:
git clone https://github.com/2kabhishek/links cd links Setup Your Own links You can easily set up links to show your own profiles.</description></item><item><title>Projects - Showcase All Your Projects 🛍️🎇</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/articles/projects-showcase-github/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 11:36:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/articles/projects-showcase-github/</guid><description>Introducing Projects Present all your projects in style with a super customizable web app! ✨
Projects uses the GitHub API to list all your GitHub projects in a nice searchable grid. Also shows pretty programming icons using devicons.
Inspiration Needed a way to display all my projects, used my portfolio&amp;rsquo;s project section as inspiration.
Getting Projects To get projects, follow these steps:
git clone https://github.com/2kabhishek/projects cd projects Setup Your Own Projects You can easily set up projects to show your own repos.</description></item><item><title>MySQL Daemon Startup Fix 🛠️🕵️</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/articles/fix-mysql-daemon-startup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 11:54:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/articles/fix-mysql-daemon-startup/</guid><description>Problem Brief: MySQL daemon fails to start
Details: So, I recently installed MariaDB (Community fork of MySQL) on my Manjaro system and when I started the system with:
sudo systemctl start mysqld
This is the error I get:
Job for mariadb.service failed because the control process exited with error code.
Let&amp;rsquo;s look at journalctl -xe:
A start job for unit mariadb.service has finished with a failure.
Not very helpful, let&amp;rsquo;s look at mysqld&amp;rsquo;s status with: systemctl status mysqld</description></item><item><title>Navigating JavaScript 🤷‍♂️🧭</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/articles/navigating-javascript/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 09:31:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/articles/navigating-javascript/</guid><description>JavaScript is taking the world by storm, once used to add functionality to the web, now it is being used in almost all types of software development.
For example, Using JavaScript you can do things like build Progressive Web Apps (web apps with native app like features) , create desktop apps using electron, make Android &amp;amp; iOS apps with React Native, do server stuff using Node and Express and many more.</description></item></channel></rss>