<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Internet on 2KAbhishek Blogs</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/tags/internet/</link><description>Recent content in Internet on 2KAbhishek Blogs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>iam2kabhishek@gmail.com (2KAbhishek)</managingEditor><webMaster>iam2kabhishek@gmail.com (2KAbhishek)</webMaster><copyright>2KAbhishek</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 10:48:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/tags/internet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Two Factor Authentication 🔏👤</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/post/two-factor-authentication/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 10:48:00 +0530</pubDate><author>iam2kabhishek@gmail.com (2KAbhishek)</author><guid>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/post/two-factor-authentication/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In a previous post, I wrote about password managers and why you should have one.
In this follow-up article I&amp;rsquo;ll try to explain Two-Factor Authentication or 2FA and how it can make your security more robust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what 2FA does is that It adds another layer to your security.
After you provide your username and password 2FA will ask for a special code that you may receive via SMS or an authenticator app.
You can only login after providing the 2FA code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now, even if someone manages to get their hands on your login credentials they still won&amp;rsquo;t be able to access your account.
2FA is not unbreakable, but it is more secure than passwords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the online services provide 2FA including Google, Facebook, Twitter, GitHub, Steam etc.
You can setup 2FA for your account by going to the security settings of that platform.
You can also visit &lt;a href="https://twofactorauth.org/"target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;twofactorauth&lt;/a&gt; to check if a service provides 2FA or not.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Password Managers 101 🔑🌐</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/post/password-managers-101/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 22:45:00 +0530</pubDate><author>iam2kabhishek@gmail.com (2KAbhishek)</author><guid>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/post/password-managers-101/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;All of us have at least 20 (definitely more!) accounts on the internet today and managing all those passwords can get tricky if not done correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can easily forget your password and if you don&amp;rsquo;t you have a very easy to guess password, and that is a very terrible thing to do.
You also have to remember other information like credit card informations, licence keys, secure notes etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple solution to those problems is a password manager.
A password manager creates a database of your passwords, username and other details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those passwords could then be easily synced across your devices and with things like autofill they make the whole online experience much simpler to everyone without worrying about a gazillion passwords.
You do have to remember the master password for your specific database and that&amp;rsquo;s a necessary evil.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>