<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Side-Projects on 2KAbhishek Blogs</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/tags/side-projects/</link><description>Recent content in Side-Projects on 2KAbhishek Blogs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>©2023 2KAbhishek</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 08:28:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/tags/side-projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nerdy.nvim - Find Nerd Glyphs Easily 🤓🔭</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/nerdy.nvim-find-nerd-glyphs-easily/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 08:28:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/nerdy.nvim-find-nerd-glyphs-easily/</guid><description>Do you like Nerd fonts? but don&amp;rsquo;t like going over to their site just to fetch a glyph for your pretty terminal?
Well, me too!
Introducing nerdy.nvim, a super handy plugin that lets you easily search, preview and insert all nerd font glyphs straight from neovim!
✨ Features Fuzzy search nerd glyphs Preview glyphs before inserting Super lightweight Can auto generate new icons from source Setup ⚡ Requirements You have installed the latest version of neovim These two plugins are optional but highly recommended for a smoother user experience.</description></item><item><title>win2k - Ultimate Dev Setup for Windows 🪟🪄</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/win2k-ultimate-dev-setup-for-windows/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/win2k-ultimate-dev-setup-for-windows/</guid><description>Do you find the Windows dev environment lacking? Do you miss your precious CLI tools on Windows?
Well I felt the same way too. That&amp;rsquo;s why I combined a package manager, a powerful CLI editor, tiling window management and lots of other tools in a easy to set up solution.
Introducing win2k win2k is a set of handcrafted configs for setting up a complete dev environment on Windows.
It makes developing on Windows much more pleasant for CLI lovers.</description></item><item><title>tmux-tilit - better tiling for tmux 🪟🪓</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/tmux-tilit-better-tiling-for-tmux/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:58:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/tmux-tilit-better-tiling-for-tmux/</guid><description>If you have used tmux then you already know that tmux provides ways to create multiple panes on your terminal among many other things.
You might have also felt that the default way of doing these things is kind of clumsy and doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel natural.
Introducing tmux-tilit: What is this tmux-tilit is a tmux plugin that adds tiling window manager like features and keybindings to tmux.
Inspiration tmux-tilit was inspired by tmux-tilish.</description></item><item><title>Co-author.nvim - Add commit authors from nvim 💻🪄</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/co-author.nvim-add-commit-authors-from-nvim/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 10:28:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/co-author.nvim-add-commit-authors-from-nvim/</guid><description>What is this How many times have you been working on a piece of code with someone and then when committing you ask their full name and email address for adding a Co-author to the commit?
Upgrade to 21st century, use this plugin to automatically fetch author details from your commit history and then add to your commit message, all from inside neovim.
It shows you a list of all the unique authors in your current repo.</description></item><item><title>Posh2K - A universal prompt for power users 💪🌈</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/posh2k-a-universal-prompt-for-power-users/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:58:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/posh2k-a-universal-prompt-for-power-users/</guid><description>What is this Posh2K is a prompt for oh-my-posh, it works on all shells, has multiple segments with aesthetically pleasing colors.
Inspiration Most of my workflow is based on the command line, recently I had to use a Windows system for some work and was really displeased by the CLI experience.
So, I needed a prompt that can work across shells and has support for different segments and Posh2K was born.</description></item><item><title>Tmux2K - Power &amp; Pizzazz for tmux 🥊💅</title><link>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/tmux2k-power-pizzazz-for-tmux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:58:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://2kabhishek.github.io/blog/tmux2k-power-pizzazz-for-tmux/</guid><description>What is this tmux2k is a tmux plugin for that adds powerline support and pretty colors to your tmux status bar.
Inspiration tmux2k was inspired by dracula/tmux.
Prerequisites Before you begin, ensure you have met the following requirements:
You have installed the latest version of tmux. tpm for managing tmux plugins. A patched nerd font for powerline and glyphs support. Installing tmux2k Using tpm
If you are a tpm user, you can install the theme and keep up to date by adding the following to your .</description></item></channel></rss>